+1(647) 795-2914



doshimilin56@gmail.com



Brampton, ON Canada



EDUCATION

Masters (Embedded Electrical & Computer System Engineering) - San Francisco State University (California, USA) - 2016

Bachelors (Electronics & Communication Engineering)
L.J Institute
(Gujarat, India) - 2013

KEY SKILLS

Front - End UI Development



UX – Development



Back - End & Database



Project Management



Problem Solving & Leadership



Architecture & Design



& Curriculum Activities

Attended So Many Meetups & Hackathons

Winner of Hackathon Tedhack-2016 organized by CISCO

Winner of Wired-Logic Competitions in 2011 & 2012

CERTIFICATIONS

Safe-4 Practitioner

Lynda.com, Udemy & Other Online Courses

MILIN DOSHI

Portfolio: www.milindoshi.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/milin-y/

GitHub: www.github.com/doshimilin57

Front End UI / UX Developer -

Profile Summary

Web Developer with almost 5 years of Experience in Designing and Developing User interfaces, Testing, Debugging and creating Architecture of High Scalable Multi-Tired Web Applications.

Technical Skills

Languages / Scripts/ Frameworks / Database / IDEs

HTML4/5, DHTML, XHTML, CSS, CSS3, SASS, LESS, Bootstrap 3/4, JSP, Gulp, Grunt, Webpack, NPM, Node JS, Java, Spring Framework, Struts, Microservices, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular JS 1/2/4/8, React JS, Redux, SQL, NonSQL, PL/SQL, MongoDB, Db2, PostgreSQL, Adobe illustrator, Dreamweaver, WCAG, Visual Studio, Sublime text, Eclipse, WebStorm, Atom, REST/SOAP Services

Professional Experiences

Mercedes-Benz Financial Services (Consultant) – United Business Solutions, Detroit, MI(U.S.A)–(March 2017 – Present)

Sr. Front-End UI / UX Developer – mbfs.com

Description: The project is to create the customer portal / website for Mercedes Car owners. The website has all the functionality including Apply for Credit, Payments, Statements, Documents, Payoff Quotes, Virtual Assistant, Live Chat and many more.

UI / UX Developer – fipro2.i.daimler.com

Description: The project was to create the dealer portal / website for Daimler's truck dealers. When the customer wants to buy vehicle either individual or fleet customer, the web application has all the functionality from creating a credit application to quoting, funding, contracting, insuring and payments etc.

Environments: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap 4, Responsive Web Design, Angular Material, Typescript, Angular 1/2/4/8, ECMASript (ES6), RxJS, NgRx, JSON, XML, JSP, Gulp, Node JS, Ionic, NPM, Bower, Webpack, ESLint, InVision, Zeplin, GIT, SVN, Spring, JAVA 8, Microservices, SonarQube, AWS, Eclipse, REST, PL/SQL, Db2, OAuth, Rapid SQL, Visual Studio, WebStorm, Karma, Jasmine, CICD Process, Agile Scrum, SAFE-4, JIRA, Confluence, Bamboo, Google Analytics, TDD

AT&T (Consultant) – Srimad Solutions, Irving, TX (U.S.A)

Front-End UI Developer – (November 2016 – January 2017)

Description: My project was to create one global online educational portal where anyone inside the AT&T can create courses and other people can take those courses online. They can also do the discussion with other subject matter expert related to that course, rate and like them as well as they can earn certificate for that course if they pass the exams.

Environments: HTML, CSS, LESS, Bootstrap 3, Responsive Web Design, Typescript, React JS, Redux, JSON, ColdFusion, Apache Tomcat, Adobe illustrator, GIT, JAVA, Agile Scrum, Sublime Text, Atom, JWT, PostgreSQL, Jenkins, Analytics

Novatrice Technologies - Ahmedabad, GJ (India)

Software Engineer - (June 2013 - August 2014)

Description: Worked on multiple projects which includes different domains like Healthcare, eCommerce, Banking.

Environments: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Dreamweaver, Drupal, .Net, PHP, AJAX, WordPress, Eclipse, SQL, SharePoint, Notepad++, Photoshop